嘿，大家好，我是TheCherno，欢迎回到我的游戏引擎系列
hey, what's up guys, my name is TheCherno, welcome back to my game engine series
那么上期我们创建了一个ImGuiLayer，如果你们还没有看过的话，一定要去看看那期视频
so last time we took a little creating the ImGuiLayer, definitely check out that video, if you haven't already
在那期视频的最后，我给你们留下了一个小小的挑战
and at the end of that video, I left you guys with a bit of a challenge
也就是尝试并实现了ImGuiLayer的整个事件系统
which was try and implement the whole event system for the ImGuiLayer
因为我们所做的只是一种渲染，只是更新并初始化和设置所有ImGui
because what we had done was just kind of rendering and just updating and getting all of ImGui initialized and set up
我们在屏幕上看到了一些东西，但我们当然无法与之互动
and we were seeing stuff on the screen, but of course we couldn't interact with that
我们不能使用鼠标或键盘之类的东西，而挑战是给你们的
we couldn't use the mouse or the keyboard or anything like that, and the challenge was for you guys
要自己尝试使用Hazel的事件系统实现那个，因为视频提前一周发布给赞助人
to try and implement that yourself, using Hazel's event system, so because the video is out a week early for patrons
我们已经就可能的解决方案进行了一些非常重要的讨论，这很酷
we've had some pretty crucial discussions about possible solutions to that, which is pretty cool
所以首先，如果你们在patreon上还没支持我，一定要看看patreon.com/thecherno
so first of all, if you're not supporting me on patreon, definitely check that out, patreon.com/thecherno
所有的视频都是一个月前一周发布的
all the videos are released of a, what's going to say on month early a week early
你们还可以进入Hazel的一个私有开发分支，就像我在业余时间在搞Hazel一样
and you also get access to a private development branch of Hazel, which is like me working on Hazel in my spare time
那比我们这里实际拥有的要多得多
that's a lot a lot a lot a lot a lot bigger than what we actually have here
总之，我们确实在Discord上的的赞助人频道中讨论过那个
so anyway, so we did actually discuss that in the patrons channel on Discord
看到你们中的很多人都在尝试挑战，真的很酷
so that was really cool to see how a lot of you guys actually attempted that challenge
最终提出了自己的解决方案和实现
and ended up coming up with your own kind of solutions and implementations
今天我们要看一看我实现这个的基本方法，我可以点明的这些例子
and today we're just going to take a look at basically the way that I did it, these exercises could I just point out
我知道很多人一直要求我做这样的事情，我也一直在尝试做这样的事情
I know that a lot of people have been asking me to do stuff like that, and I've been trying to do stuff like that
因为你们看了之后就开始做自己的事情
because this kind of interaction between you guys watching it and then going off and doing your own thing
很多时候，我只是假设这是存在的，不管怎样，举个例子
that's something that a lot of the time I just kind of assume exists, anyway, so for example
你们知道，你们创建的，你们写下视频中的所有内容，然后自定义它
you know, you make, you write down everything from this video, but then you customize it
因为你们在构建自己的引擎或类似的东西，对吧，或者你们改变它
because you're making your own engine or something like that, right, or you change it
或者你们只是在业余时间继续写，在下期视频中，你们也可以整合我所做的一切
or you just keep working on it in your spare time, and in the next video comes out, and you integrate whatever I've done as well
那那有点像你们正在做的一个不断发展的项目，而不仅仅是每周视频发布的时候
and that's it's kind of like an ever evolving kind of project that you're working on, not just when the video comes out every week
但是整个一周或者任何你们有空闲时间的时候，但是因为很多人都不这样对待它
but just all throughout the week or wherever you have spare time, but because a lot of people kind of don't treat it like that
我认为这是一个好主意，显然提供这样的练习，当你们这样做的时候
I think it is kind of a good idea, obviously to provide exercises like that, and when you do that when you kind of
当我给你们挑战时，我真的希望你们去做，因为首先，我不认为它们太难
when I give you guys challenges, I really want you to do them, because first of all, I don't think they're too difficult
或者我认为它们不一定需要我，只是需要编写代码
or I don't think they're necessarily need me, it's just code that needs to be written
它不像你们知道的那样，像这个主要的新特性那样进行架构，顺便说一句，即使它是
it's not like you know, architecting like this major new feature, which by the way, even if it was
你们还是可以试试看，看看有什么不对的，你们应该这样做
you could still give that a shot, and see what you come up with nothing wrong with that, you should do that in fact
但是你们真正要学习的唯一方法是亲自编写代码，并尝试自己设计和编写代码
but the only way you're really going to learn is by actually writing code yourself and trying to come up with designs and code yourself
因此，练习非常重要，无需进一步的计划
so exercises super important without further ado
让我们看看如何将ImGui与Hazel的事件系统集成
let's see how we can get ImGui integrated with Hazel's event system
这可能是我们第一次正确使用事件调度器，我很期待
this is probably the first time we're going to use the event dispatcher properly as well, which I'm looking forward to
因为人们一直在问这个问题，是的，到最后
because people have been asking about that, and yeah by the end
我的意思是，总之，我们应该能够在ImGui中输入内容
I mean by the end of today, we should have, we should be able to type stuff into ImGui
然后移动窗口，使用鼠标和滚动等等，那么看看我们能做些什么
and move the window around, and use the mouse and scroll, and all of that kind of stuff, so let's see what we can do
好了，那么如果我们像现在这样运行Hazel，看看有什么，基本上就是这些
okay, so if we just kind of launch Hazel as it is now, just to see what we have, it's basically this
我们看到了ImGui演示窗口，但你们可以看到，我们显然无法与之交互
we see the ImGui demo window, but you can see, we obviously can't interact with it
是的，真的很无聊，所以实际上得把这些交互加入其中
and yeah it's pretty boring, so to actually add that kind of interaction to it
我们可以从GLFW实现中复制代码，因为你们可以看到它的作用是
one thing that we can kind of steal code from is that GLFW implementation, because you can see what this does is
你们知道，GLFW会触发某些事件，它们会在这里的某个地方发生
you know, we have certain events to get triggered from GLFW, and they'll be here somewhere
就像你们知道的，有一个向后滚动，一个按键回调，一个滚动回调，一个鼠标按钮回调
so like you know, there's a scroll back, a key callback, scroll back, a scroll callback, a mouse button callback
你们可以看到它的实际功能，实际上设置了g_MouseJustPressed，然后在循环中更新
and you can see what it actually does, well this one actually sets g_MouseJustPressed and then updates in the update loop
但可以看到，对于KeyCallback，如果按下按键，然后ImGui::GetIO()，也就是ImGuiIO，对吧
but you can see that for the KeyCallback for example, it just if the key is pressed, then ImGui::GetIO(), which is ImGuiIO, right
如果io.KeysDown[key] = true，那么那个就是我们要在按键容器中设置的key
it says io.KeysDown, with the key as the index equals true, and that indexible key is kind of what we set in this key map
所以那就是它的原理，考虑到那一点，那就是从imgui_impl_glfw得到灵感的
so that's kind of how it works, so with that in mind, that's kind of where this is inspired from imgui_impl_glfw
那也是ImGui仓库的一部分，我们将基本上实现它，但我们自己可能会更干净一些
which is part of the ImGui repository, we're going to implement basically that, but ourselves and probably a little bit cleaner
我不知道我们是否真的能实现所有的事情，因为它很大，而且很多都不是
and I don't know, if we'll actually get to do everything, because it's quite large, and a lot of it's not
那就是我需要的，就像你们知道的，剪贴板上的文本和类似的小东西，可能以后可以做
that's how I needed, like you know, clipboard text and stuff like that minor things, that can probably be done later
我甚至可以把它作为你们的练习，但主要的是我们今天会搞定
I might even leave that as an exercise for you guys, but the main stuff is what we're gonna get done today
这样我们就可以开始使用ImGui了，好了，那么我想做的第一件事就是看到ImGuiLayer.h
so that we can actually start using ImGui, okay, so the first thing I wanna do is go to ImGuiLayer.h
我们实际上需要实现一系列这样的函数
and we actually need to implement a bunch of these kind of functions
所以我喜欢将私有变量与函数分开，只是为了让它更容易一些
so I like to separate private variables from functions, just to make it a little bit easier
但基本上，我们需要几乎所有的事件
but basically we're gonna need pretty much every every event we have
所以ButtonPress，那么就是OnMouseButtonPressedEvent
so ButtonPress, so OnMouseButtonPressedEvent
就是一个MouseButtonPressedEvent，我们还有OnMouseButtonReleasedEvent
which is a MouseButtonPressedEvent, we have OnMouseButtonReleasedEvent
我们可能还需要包含一些头文件，MouseMove MouseScroll，MouseMoved，scrolled
and we'll have to probably include a bunch of headers here as well, MouseMove MouseScroll, MouseMoved, scrolled
然后我们有，让我们看看按键的按下释放和输入，输入是我们可能需要添加的事件
and then we have, let's see key press release typed, typed is something we might actually have to add
然后是WindowResize，这些都是我能想到的
and then the WindowResize as well, those are all the ones I can think of
那么就是OnWindowResized，至于这个OnKeyTyped，我想我们没有一个KeyTyped
so OnWindowResized, OnKeyTyped, I don't think we have a KeyTypeed
那么我们可能必须实现那个，因为ImGui需要那个
then we might have to implement that, because ImGui's going to want that
所以KeyTypedEvent本质上就是，如果你们点击一个字符代码按键，它就像输入
and then so KeyTypedEvent is essentially, if you hit a character code key, and it kind of counts as like typing
输入实际字符，然后是KeyReleased和KeyPressed
typing an actual character, KeyReleased, and KeyPressed
那么就是MouseButtonPressed，MouseButtonReleased，MouseMoved，MouseScrolled
okay, so MouseButtonPressed, MouseButtonReleased, MouseMoved, MouseScrolled
KeyPressed，KeyReleased，KeyTyped，糟糕，应该是Event
KeyPressed, KeyReleased, KeyTyped, oops event
然后是WindowResizeEvent，好了，我们可以称之为WindowResize，所以必须包含
and then WindowResizeEvent, okay, so and we might just call that WindowResize, so we'll have to include
也就是Hazel/Events/KeyEvent，和MouseEvent，差不多了，好了，很好
if it's Hazel/Events/KeyEvent, MouseEvent, and yeah it seems to have everything, okay, great
那就是我们所有的东西，可以看到，相当多，至于KeyTypedEvent，现在先注释掉
so that's all of our stuff you can see, this quite a lot, the KeyTypedEvent, I'll comment that out for now
我们稍后再讨论，先让它跑起来，让我们点击OK来生成所有这些
we'll talk about that later, we'll get this working first, let's hit okay to that just to generate all of these
这就是乐趣的开始，所以我们需要做的第一件事是，显然这些都应该是bool，所以那很好
and this is where the fun begins, so the first thing we need to do is to, and obviously this should all be bool, so that's great
因此需要做的第一件事就是，如果这样做的话，我们可以在这个范围内用bool来代替void
so the first thing we need to do, let's just if we just do that we can replace void with bool just in that scope
好了，那么我们要做的第一件事实际上是调度所有这些事件
okay, so the first thing we need to do is actually dispatch all of these kind of events
所以我这样做的方式是使用事件来进行特殊处理，所以我的意思是当一个事件进入层时
so the way that I do that is using our event to special, so what I mean is when an event gets kind of comes into the layer
我们需要一种方法来检查事件类型，然后根据事件类型将该事件转发到其中一个函数上
we need a way to check the event type, and then forward that event onto one of these functions depending on what it is
如果是KeyPressEvent，我们想转到KeyPressEvent函数，因此可以使用EventDispatcher
if it's a KeyPressEvent, we want to go to this KeyPressEvent function, so to do that, we can use the EventDispatcher
所以我们基本上是在栈上创建这个dispatcher对象，当然就是dispatcher(event)
so we basically create this dispatcher object here on the stack, of course dispatcher with the event
需要做的就是dispatch.Dispatcher()，然后事件类型，所以第一个是MouseButtonPressEvent
and then all we need to do is type in Dispatcher dispatch and then the event type, so our first one is the MouseButtonPressEvent
所以从字面上看，这个MouseButtonPressEvent就是这样
so literally this MouseButtonPressEvent, and then that's it
所以如果这个事件与这个事件类型匹配，就会发生什么
and so what will happen is if this event matches this event type
这就是dispatch函数检查的内容，然后它将实际调用我们将在此处指定的函数
which is what the dispatch function checks for, then it will actually call this function that we're about to specify here
现在我们使用这个，我们在WindowsWindow中基本上做了同样的事情
now we use this, we basically kind of do the same thing in our WindowsWindow
当我们在这里处理lambders和所有回调时，有点类似，我们可以在这里设置lambda
when we dealt with lambders over here with all the callbacks, it's kind of similar, we could set a lambda here
当然，我们有一个实际的函数，所以要设置它，需要绑定它
but of course we've got an actual function, so to set it up, we need to bind it
因为这个函数当然是ImGuiLayer的成员
because this function of course is a member of ImGuiLayer
那么长话短说，我们需要做一些类似std::bind的事情，你们知道的，这个实际的函数
so long story short, we need to do something that's like std bind, you know this actual function
所以它看起来像&ImGuiLayer::MouseButtonPressedEvent，然后
so it would look like an ImGuiLayer, and then that, and then
我们需要绑定到this，然后就是std::placeholder::_1，就像那样
we need to bind this, and then you know std::placeholder, one look kind of like that
这个应该是OnMouseButtonPressEvent
and this is OnMouseButtonPressEvent
就像这样，我的意思是完全一样，好吧，那就是我们需要做的，现在很明显这看起来很混乱
and by kind of like that, I mean exactly like that, okay, so that's what we need to do, now obviously this looks very messy
所以我想做的是定义一个宏，我会把它和所有其他东西一起放进我们的Core.h文件中
so what I want to do is actually make a macro out of this, and I'm actually going to put this into our kind of Core header file with all of the other stuff
就叫它HZ_BIND_EVENT_FN，我们基本上要把它粘贴在这里
I'm going to call it HZ_BIND_EVENT_FN, and we're basically gonna paste that in here
然后这一块就换成fn，就这样做，就是fn，好了
and then the only thing I want to really take away is just this x I'll call fn, this so we just do and fn, okay
然后我说，但我是说当然是fn的引用，好了
and then I'm saying, and but I mean anne for sandwich of course is the reference of fn, okay
那只需要用一个占位符将其绑定到该函数中，好了，所以现在变成了我们仍然保留这部分
and that's just gonna bind this with a single placeholder into that function, okay, so this now becomes we still keep this part
但这现在变成了那样的HZ_BIND_EVENT_FN，好了，那看起来干净多了
but this now becomes HZ_BIND_EVENT_FN like that, okay, and that looks a lot clean up
现在我们需要做的是基本上做相同的事情，但对于所有其他事件，我可能会快速过一遍
and now what we need to do is basically do the exact same, but for all of the other events, so I'm just gonna probably fast forward through that
因为那可能需要一点时间，好了，所以那就是所有的代码
because that might take a bit of time, okay, so that's all of the code done here
所以现在将发生的是，每当ImGui实际接收到事件时，它都会尝试查看事件的类型
so now what will happen is whenever ImGui actually receives an event, it'll try to see what type is
然后传递到适当的函数，这很好
and then propagated to the appropriate function, which is great
所以现在我们可以开始实现七个事件发生时会发生什么，那么鼠标按钮按下和释放非常简单
so now we can actually start implementing what happens when seven events happen, so mouse button press release is quite easy
我们需要做的就是得到那个ImGuiIO，我想，就是ImGui::GetIO()
all we need to do is actually get that ImGuiIO, which is I think ImGui::GetIO()
然后简单地看一下，MouseDown[e.GetMouseButton()] = true
and then simply see that, MouseDown with the actual mouse button, it's true
好了，然后我们会返回false，这意味着我们处理这个事件
okay, and then we'll return false, meaning we haven't handled this
返回false的原因是我们希望其他层可以处理这个事件
the reason we return false is because we want other layers to potentially handle this
因为你们知道，我们并没有检查鼠标是否被二次点击
because you know it's not like we've checked to see if the mouse has actually been pressed over a second button
因此，我们不想让，你们知道的，比如其他层查找那个事件
and thus we don't want to you know kind of have other layers seek out that event
对吧，现在你们知道了，无论我们在哪里点击，都要等待，不希望这个层消费鼠标事件
right, now it's just kind of you know wait wherever we click, we don't want this layer to consume every single mouse event ever
所以那就是为什么我们返回false，如果我们想，当然可以检测到按钮是否被点击
so that's why we kind of leave it, it's false for now, if we wanted to we could of course detect whether a button was actually clicked
如果点击了一个按钮，那么很明显鼠标就在按钮上方，我们不希望其他层得到那个
and if a button was clicked, then obviously the mouse is over the button, and we don't want other layers to get that
但那太难了，所以我们现在不打算那么做
but that's just too hard, so we're not going to do that right now
至于MouseButtonReleaseEvent，再说一次，非常简单
MouseButtonReleaseEvent, again, really easy
只需要返回false，每当鼠标移动时，我们都想设置位置，所以那也很容易
we just set it to false, whenever the mouse moves, we want to set the position, so that's again easy
我们只是看看io.MousePos，现在这个是ImVec2，然后就调用e.GetX()，e.GetY()
we just see io.MousePos, now this is ImVec2, and then we just do e.GetX(), e.GetY()
并且就是那样，这个ScrolledEvent，非常简单
and that is that, ScrolledEvent, really easy as well
我们要做的是，我想这是MouseWheel，有两个MouseWheel
what we have to do is say, I think this is MouseWheel, there's two MouseWheel
有垂直的，也有个水平的，我们实际上都支持，所以我们可以同时实现这两个
there's the vertical and there's the horizontal one, we actually support both, so we might as well implement both
那么就是io.MouseWheel += e.GetXOffset()，这个MouseWheelH+=e.GetYOffset()
so this just this kind of MouseWheel just becomes plus equals e.GetXOffset, and then H is the yOffset
当然，我好像搞反了，所以水平方向是X，垂直方向是Y，就是那样，现在已经记住了
and of course I mean the other around, so horizontal is x and verticals y, and that's that, now already with this in mind
应该让所有鼠标事件都跑起来，所以如果我们运行这个
we should have all the mouse events working, so if we actually run this
我们应该能够移动窗口，像展开成员之类的
we should be able to move our window around and like expand members and stuff
好了，这儿有一些错误，那么确定没有找到WindowResizeEvent，显然应该包含那个的
okay, so we've got some errors here, okay, so identify a WindowResizeEvent is not found, apparently we should include
我想可能会包含那个，但显然没有，那么就是ApplicationEvent.h，让我们再试一次
I thought they might include that, but of course they don't, ApplicationEvent.h, let's try again apparently
我们已经生成了另一个构造函数或类似的东西，那可能也是视觉辅助
we've generated another constructor or something like that, that was probably visual assist as well
我们可以去掉它，运行一下，这儿还有一堆没有返回值的函数
yep we can get rid of that, f5, and we have a bunch of functions here that return no values
所以我们将把return false放在所有这些我们还没有实现的函数中，好了，f5运行这个
so we'll just put return false into all of these functions that we have not yet implemented, ok, f5 force run this
好了，酷，所以你们可以看到，现在很明显我可以悬浮在这个上面
okay, cool, so you can see that now obviously I can hover over this
我可以点击，我可以看到一切
I can click and I can see everything
我可以点击并拖动，可以移动所有的东西
I can click and drag, and I move everything around
所以这一切都很好地结合在一起，而且效果也很好
so this is coming together pretty nicely, and it works pretty well
我也可以滚动，所以如果我展开更多，你们可以看到，我也可以在这里使用滚轮滚动
I like to scroll as well, so if I expand more of these, you can see, I can use a scroll wheel here to scroll as well
所以到目前为止，所有这些都非常有效
so all of that is working so far awesome
所以现在我只想实现KeyPressed、keyreased和KeyTyped事件
so now I just want to implement the KeyPressed, KeyReleased, and the KeyTyped events
除了WindowResizeEvent之外，让我们先实现WindowResizeEvent
as well as the WindowResizeEvent, let's do the WindowResizeEvent first
那是我们剩下的唯一一个非关键事件
that's kind of the only non key event that we have left
所以我将io复制到这里，然后将DisplaySize设置为ImVec2(e.GetWidth(), e.GetHeight())
so I'll copy io over here, and then I'm going to set the DisplaySize to be ImVec2 e.GetWidth, e.GetHeight
以及DisplayFramebufferScale
and the DisplayFramebufferScale
所以这是我们暂时不会碰的东西，所以我要确保它被设置为ImVec2(1.0f, 1.0f)
so this is something that we're not gonna touch for now, so I'm just gonna make sure that it's set to 1, 1
我现在要做的是，在这件事上我可能真的不应该做
and what I'm going to do for now, which again I probably shouldn't really do in this
不，我绝对不应该设置视口，因为我们需要设置渲染视口
well no, I definitely shouldn't do is set the viewport, because we need to set the rendering viewport
所以现在，我要再次将其设置为(0, 0, e.GetWidth(), e.GetHeight())
so for now, again I'm going to set that to 0, 0, GetWidth() and GetHeight()
这将确保我们在调整大小后实际渲染到新屏幕区域
this will just ensure that we actually render to that new screen area after a resize has happened
当然我会的，所以这是暂时的，所以我们不应该在这里停止
and for that of course I will, so this is temporary, so we should not be including the stop this here
我要包含Glad，实际上我把它们改成角括号
I'm going to include Glad, and actually I change these to be angular brackets
因为那个文件不在这个模块中，好了，我们继续
because that file is not located in this module, okay, there we go
那么现在我们应该知道WindowResize应该可以运行了
so now we should you know WindowResize should work
那么，让我们编译这个，看看我们得到了什么
so let's just compile this, and see what we get
好了，如果我调整窗口的大小，使其变小或变大
okay, so if I resize the window and make it like tiny or really big
你们应该看到，我可以将它移动到另一个额外的屏幕区域
you should see that I'm able to move it into that other that extra screen area
这很好，好了，很酷，所以调整大小很好，那么KeyPressEvent
which is good, okay, cool, so resizing is fine, so on KeyPressEvent
有点类似于鼠标的东西，在某种意义上，我们只需要使用KeysDown，代替MouseDown
this is going to be kind of similar to the mouse stuff, in the sense that we just need to do KeysDown instead of MouseDown
那么就是KeysDown[e.GetKeyCode()] = true，然后KeyReleased这里也是一样的
so KeysDown[e.GetKeyCode()] = true, and then the same thing happened to for here released
但我们将其设置为false，但不同的是，我们实际上需要设置潜在的修改器关键点
but we set it to false, but the difference is that we actually need to set potential modifier keys
那么比如io.KeyCtrl，我们需要检测被按下
so io.KeyCtrl for example, we check to see whether or not
我们现在必须再次使用GLFW键码，因为那是我们绑定的
and again we have to use GLFW keycodes for now, because that's what we've bound to
但不管控制键是否按下，或者我猜是右控制键
but whether or not the control is down, or I guess the right control as well
所以那就是LEFT_CONTROL，我们将复制它，然后改成RIGHT_CONTROL
so that's LEFT_CONTROL, we'll copy that and call it RIGHT_CONTROL
好了，我们需要对所有修改键执行相同的操作，所以我们还有Shift、Alt和Super
okay, so that's we need to do the same for all modify keys, so we have also Shift and Alt and Super
所以Super是Windows键，取决于所在的平台，可以看到它是MAC上的一个Command键
so super is the Windows key, kind of you know depends on the platform you're on, you can see it's a command key on MAC
那就是为什么它被称为Super，而不像Windows键，因为这当然不仅仅是关于Windows的
that's why it's called super, and not like Windows key, because of course this isn't just about Windows
就是LEFT_SUPER，RIGHT_SUPER，RIGHT_ALT，RIGHT_SHIFT，LEFT_SHIFT，LEFT_ALT
so LEFT_SUPER, RIGHT_SUPER, RIGHT_ALT, RIGHT_SHIFT, LEFT_SHIFT, LEFT_ALT
好了，我们继续，所以每次按下一个键，我们检查是否基本上也按下了一个修改器
okay, there we go, so every time a key is pressed, we check to see if a modifier is also pressed basically
然后还是默认返回false，所以如果我们按，它也会触发我们设置的那个
and then we said that modified its true fault, so if we had , and it triggers that we also set this as well
然后在任何地方检查，如果我们需要的话，基本上是按s键，所以那就是方法，非常简单
and then that gets checked where whatever you know, s is pressed, if we need to basically, so that's the idea, it's super simple
然后我们终于有了KeyTyped，这应该还没有实现，所以我要把它还原
and then we finally have KeyTyped, which should we have not implemented yet, so I'm gonna bring this back
这应该不会太难，所以我们今天就把它塞进去，我不会把它留到下一期
this shouldn't be too difficult, so we're just gonna jam that in today, I'm not gonna save this for another episode
因为我们不得不浪费时间，即使在这里把它分得很细
because we have to waste that time, even though we are cutting it pretty thin here
所以就是ImGuiLayer::OnKeyTypedEvent
so we have ImGuiLayer OnKeyTyped
好了，那么这里的想法就是，我们甚至可以先看看我们想做什么，然后再确定事件类型
okay, so the idea here, and we might even just look at what we want to do first, and before we make the event type
但基本上这是在任何时候，这也在这里
but basically this is whenever, and this is also in here
我相信在某个地方，它在这里，所以它被称为glfwCharCallback
I believe somewhere, here it is, so it's called it's the glfwCharCallback
如果发生这种情况，我们就是AddInputCharacter，然后复制它，粘贴到这里
so essentially if this happens, we AddInputCharacter, so let's copy that, it's pasted into here
顺便说一下，那在imgui_impl_glfw中，所以那就是我们的字符代码，然后加上return false
that was in imgui_impl_glfw by the way, so this is our character code, and then we'll add return false
这基本上是用来在文本框中键入类似的东西，所以要用GLFW设置它，我们必须做一些事情
and this is used for like typing stuff typing wise into a text box essentially, so to set this up with GLFW, we have to do a few things
首先，我将进入KeyEvent并实际创建该事件类型，因此我将复制KeyPressEvent
first of all, I'm going to go into KeyEvent and actually make that event type, so I'll copy the KeyPressEvent
我想这应该很简单，我会把它粘贴到这里，然后我会把它重命名为KeyTypedEvent
I guess this should be quite simple there, and I'll paste it over here, and I'll just rename it to be a KeyTypedEvent
不会有任何重复计数或类似的事情，会有一个KeyCode，去掉它，将其改为KeyTypedEvent
there's not gonna be any repeat count or anything like that, there will be a KeyCode, get rid of this, change this to KeyTypedEvent
然后我们就不需要这些东西了，这就成了我们需要添加的KeyTyped
and then we don't need any of this stuff, this becomes KeyTyped which we need to also add
当然是KeyTyped，差不多就这样，没有重复计数，好了，所以事件类类型是KeyTyped
and this is of course KeyTyped, okay, and that is pretty much it, so no repeat count, okay, so event class type KeyTyped
我们当然需要在这里添加KeyTyped作为一个事件，所以这里变成了KeyTyped
we of course need, to add KeyTyped as an event here, so this becomes KeyTyped over here, key pressed, released, typed, great
现在我们当然需要实现它，所以在WindowsWindow中，当我们执行KeyCallback时
and now of course we need to implement it, so in WindowsWindow, when we do our KeyCallback
所以KeyCallback，我还要设置glfwSetCharCallback
so that KeyCallback, I'm also going to set glfwSetCharCallback
至于这个CharCallback，如果我们看charFn，char函数
and the CharCallback, if we look at the charFn, the char function
这很简单，只需要一个unsigned int，所以我们不需要这些，这很简单
it's really easy, it's just got an unsigned int, so we don't need any of this, it's pretty simple
这就是我们实际使用的unicode字符，所以就是character，然后得到WindowData
that's the kind of the unicode character that we actually press, so recall character, and then we just get the WindowData
我们可以这样做，也就是KeyTypedEvent，character，也许我会叫它keycode
and we can just do something like this, which is the KeyTypedEvent, character maybe I'll call a keycode just to be
只是为了让code在任何地方都是一样的，然后我们只需编写code就可以了
just so that it's code the same everywhere, and then we just code that and that should be it
所以我现在看一下命名空间，现在如果我们回到ImGuiLayer，我们要确保
so I'll just look space yet, now that now if we go back to, now ImGuiLayer, we're going to make sure that we
好了，那么就是KeyTypedEvent，很好，如果我们回到这里
okay, so KeyTypedEvent, great, we'll say if we go back to here
我想它只是一个int，所以int keycode = e.GetKeyCode()
I think it's just it's an int, so int keycode equals e.GetKeyCode()
然后这就是要检查的keycode，然后这加上keycode，不管怎么说，这是一个unsigned short
and then this is what we're checking the keycode, okay, and then we add the keycode here, it's cars into an unsigned short anyway
所以很明显，这是一个int，对于一个unsigned int根本没有问题
so obviously this being an int and on an unsigned int is no problem at all
我们不应该有那么大的按键代码
we should not have key codes that large
好了，酷，就那样，我们需要确保我们真的调度了那个循环，因为我们会先把那个注释掉
okay, cool, so that's it, we need to make sure we're actually dispatching that loop, because we do comment that out
你们可以看到它运行得很好，f5，现在应该能够在文本框中输入内容，所以测试一下
you can see that works perfectly, f5, and we should be able to type stuff into text boxes now, so let's test that out
好了，那么让我们把它移回到这里，当你们关闭时，ImGui当然会保存以前的窗口位置
okay, so let's move this back here, ImGui of course saves the previous window position when you close
所以现在我想，如果我们深入到示例和控制台之类的东西，log可能会是一个更好的地方
so now I think if we go into examples and console or something like that, log might be a better one actually
然后我们可以过滤，你们可以看到我实际上可以输入像hello之类的
then we can filter, and you can see I can actually type in like hello or whatever
15.9，因为我看到了这15.9的时间，我甚至可以做control + shift，你们知道的，就像整排一样
15.9, cause I saw time this 15.9, I can even do like control shifts, you know left just like the whole row
如果我有多个词或其他什么，你们可以看到，那是预期控制的
if I have multiple words or whatever, you can see that, that works is expected control
它还寻找我想要的东西，所以这真的很有用，当然shift复制和粘贴不起作用
also it seeks what I want, so that's like really useful, of course shift copy and paste don't work
因为我们还没有设置，所以我希望你们现在可以去尝试一下
because we haven't set that up, that's something that I want you guys to try out right now
但是你们可以看到，我们这里有一个很好的ImGui实现，现在使用的是Hazel的事件系统
but yeah you can see that we've got a pretty working implementation of ImGui here, now using Hazel's event system
实际上，我们所做的唯一提交就是这个glViewport
and really the only kind of thing that we've committed is this glViewport thing
否则，在这个事件系统中，其他一切都非常好，那几乎是最终的代码
otherwise everything else is really good in all of this event system, that's pretty much final code
那就是它的原理，很明显，按键代码只需要替换为HazelKey代码就可以了
that's how it's going to work, and obviously, the key codes just need to be replaced with HazelKey codes
但除此之外，你们可以看到使用Hazel的事件系统设置这些是多么的容易
but otherwise, you can see how easy it is to set up something like this using Hazel's event system
我们有所有这类的层和事件系统，所有的基础组件都在实际运行
l we have all of this kind of layer and event system stuff all that infrastructure actually up and running
好了，那么我希望你们喜欢这期视频，如果喜欢的话，就为它点赞吧
okay, so I hope you guys enjoyed this video, if you did, and hit the like button
你们也可以通过访问patreon.com/thecherno来支持这个系列
you can also help support this series by going to patreon.com/thecherno
非常感谢所有赞助人让系列成为可能，因为如果没有你们，就不会有这个系列
huge thank you to all the patreons that make a series possible, because it wouldn't be here without you guys
你们会得到支持，实际上你们会在一周前得到视频，所以下期视频现在就已经出来了
you'll get for supporting, you'll actually get videos a week earlier, so the next one will already be out right now
如果你们在YouTube上公开观看这段视频，还有我迄今为止写的所有这些代码
if you're watching this publicly on YouTube, and then also all this kind of code that I've written so far
我想我知道该写什么是因为我以前已经写过了
and kind of I guess how I know what to write is because I've already written it before
实际上，它是由赞助人决定的，就像所有那种Hazel的版本
and it's actually up for patrons, like all of that kind of the version of Hazel
那比实际做的要完整得多，写得也要多，更令人兴奋的事情也可以提供给赞助人
that is much more complete and much more written than actually doing, much more exciting things, is also available to patrons as well
所以再次，非常感谢，下次，我想我们要做的可能是，我的意思是我真的不喜欢这些
so again, huge thank you, next time, I think what we're going to do is probably, I mean I really don't like these
我们这里有这样的按键代码，因为我们使用的是GLFW按键代码，那肯定需要修复
these kind of key codes that we have here, cause we're using GLFW key codes, that definitely needs to be fixed
所以我们可能会输入鼠标代码，这可能有点无聊，但它仍然是值得的，除此之外，我认为
so we might do key in mouse codes, that probably might be a little bit boring, but it's still worth it, and along with that, I think
我们可能会转向我还想进行输入轮询的方向，现在我们可以在输入发生时获取事件
we'll probably move on to a direction where I wanted to also do input polling, which is right now we kind of get events for when an input happens
所以当按下一个按键时，我们会得到一个事件，但没有办法请求Hazel，嘿
so when a key is pressed, we get an event, but there's no way for us to actually ask Hazel, hey
你们知道的，现在控制键是不是按下了，鼠标键是不是按下了，鼠标左键是不是按下了
you know, is the control key down at the moment, is the mouse button, is the left mouse button, is it pressed right now
我们没有办法实现那样的事情，那对未来的某些事情肯定是有用和至关重要的
there's no way for us to do anything like that, and that's definitely going to be useful and vital for certain things in the future
因为如果我们从技术上来说有一个事件系统，是的，一切皆有可能
because if we kind of just have an event system technically, yes, anything as possible
但这意味着客户必须自己订阅，确保它们保持所有这些按键和鼠标按钮的状态
but it means the client has to order like by themselves, make sure that they kind of keep the state of all of these keys and mouse buttons
虽然我们希望Hazel在内部做到这一点，因此接口很好且简单
whereas we want Hazel to do that internally, so that the api is nice and simple
但我们可以向它查询一些东西，然后我们就会得到它
we can just ask it for something, and we'll get it
希望你们喜欢这期视频，下次见，拜
hope you guys enjoyed this video, I will see you next time, goodbye